Tel: +81-80-4235-4210 Email: zhuangchenyi@gmail.com

Background

I am a Ph.D. student (will graduate in September, 2017) at the Graduate School of Informatics, Kyoto University, where I am also serving as a research fellow in Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS). My current research primarily involves social multimedia mining and urban computing. The major techniques that I expertize on are Matrix Factorization, Probabilistic Generative Model and Graph Theory.

Education

Kyoto University

2014.10 - 2017.9

Ph.D. Degree of Informatics

Kyoto University

2012.10 - 2014.9

Master Degree of Informatics

GPA 3/3 (top 1%)

Nanjing University

2007.9 - 2011.6 & 2011.9 - 2012.9

Bachelor Degree of Software Engineering & Master Course Educated

GPA 2.86/3 (top 5%)

Research Experience

Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS)

JSPS Research Fellow

Japan 2015.4 - 2018.3

JSPS Research Fellowships for Young Scientists. The ongoing work aims to develop a sightseeing promotion system for sightseeing knowledge integration and recommendation.

Microsoft Research Asia

Intern

Beijing, China

2015.10 - 2016.1

I was serving as an intern in the Social Computing Group and devised a novel matrix factorization and neural network ensemble for modeling user mobility behavior in a city.

Kyoto University

OA & TA & RA

Kyoto, Japan

2012.10 - 2015.3

Office Assistance, Teaching Assistance and Research Assistance. For RA, I developed a regional sightseeing resource recommendation system and applied it in the real-world.

Programming Experience

Nanjing University

Software development process research group

Nanjing, China

2012.2 - 2012.9

Development of empirical theory in software engineering to improve the software quality.

Oracle Corporation & Chinese Ministry of Education

A nationwide competition

Beijing, China

2010.4 - 2010.6

We developed a Website development plugin for the IDE NetBeans, which was awarded as the outstanding innovation project (the second place) in this contest.

SIEMENS Corporation

Quality Assurance Intern

Nanjing, China

2009.7 - 2009.8

Took part in a CMMI group to learn some knowledge about quality assurance (QA).

Funding and Honors

Funding

2015 - 2018

Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) KAKENHI Grant Number 15J01402.

Honors 2007 – 2017

(2016) An Honor of Excellence in the Microsoft Research Asia Star of Tomorrow Program;

(2015) Japan Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS) Research Fellowship;

(2014) Asian Future Leaders Program Fellowship, designed by BaiXian Education Foundation;

(2012) Monbukagakusho Honors Scholarship by Japan Student Services Organization (JASSO);

(2009) Chinese National Scholarship Award and the Outstanding Student Honor;

(2008) Chinese People's Scholarship Award and the Outstanding Student Honor;

(2007) Chinese People's Scholarship Award and the Outstanding Student Honor.

I am a PSP certificated developer

Personal software process, a certification by SEI, Carnegie Mellon University.

Programming languages

Python & Theano (usually used); Java (learned); C++ (learned).

Communication

Chinese (native); English (TOEIC: 935); Japanese (a bit).

Selected Publications

Conference:

- 1. Chenyi Zhuang, Nicholas Jing Yuan, Ruihua Song, Xing Xie, Qiang Ma. Understanding People Lifestyles: Construction of Urban Movement Knowledge Graph from GPS Trajectory. International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI), Melbourne, Australia, August 2017. (Accepted, to appear)
- 2. Yizhu Shen, <u>Chenyi Zhuang</u>, Qiang Ma. Element-oriented Method of Assessing Landscape of Sightseeing Spots by using Social Images. APWeb-WAIM Joint Conference on Web and Big Data, Beijing China, July 2017. (Accepted, to appear)
- 3. Yizhu Shen, Min Ge, Chenyi Zhuang, Qiang Ma. Sightseeing Value Estimation by Analyzing Geosocial Images. IEEE International Conference on Multimedia Big Data (BigMM), pp. 117-124, Taipei, Taiwan, April 2016.
- 4. Chenyi Zhuang, Qiang Ma, Masatoshi Yoshikawa. Location Familiarity Based Flickr Photographer Classification for POI Mining. ACM International Conference on Advances in Geographic Information System (ACM SIGSPATIAL), Article No. 84, Seattle, USA, November 2015.
- 5. Chenyi Zhuang, Qiang Ma, Xuefeng Liang, Masatoshi Yoshikawa. Discovering Obscure Sightseeing Spots by Analysis of Geo-tagged Social Images. IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining (ASONAM), pp. 590-595, Paris, France, August 2015.
- Chenyi Zhuang, Qiang Ma, Xuefeng Liang, Masatoshi Yoshikawa. Anaba: An Obscure Sightseeing Spots Discovering System. IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME), pp. 1-6, Chengdu, China, July 2014.
- 7. <u>Chenyi Zhuang</u>, Qiang Ma, Xuefeng Liang, Masatoshi Yoshikawa. Discover Anaba Sightseeing Spots Using Social Images, 2013-DBS-157(9), pp. 1–6, Hokkaido, Japan, July 2013.
- 8. <u>Chenyi Zhuang, Jingyi Li, Guoping Rong, Dong Shao. APIS A Web-based System for PSP/TSP. ENASE EAST, pp. 68–74, Beijing, China, June 2011.</u>

Journal:

- 1. Chenyi Zhuang, Qiang Ma, Masatoshi Yoshikawa. SNS User Classification and its Application for Discovering Obscure POIs. Multimedia Tools and Applications. February 2017, Volume 76, Issue 4, pp. 5461-5487.
- 2. Yizhu Shen, Min Ge, <u>Chenyi Zhuang</u>, Qiang Ma. Sightseeing Value Estimation by Analyzing Geosocial Images. <u>International Journal of Big Data Intelligence</u>. 2016. (Accepted, to appear)
- 3. Guoping Rong, Chenyi Zhuang, Dong Shao. How to Write Essentially Defect-free Code: A Preliminary Study. IT Education. Computer Education Magazine. Volume 10, 2012.

Portrait

